JONATHAN HONDA

San Ramon, CA 94583 Phone: (619) 609-3407 | E-mail: hondahelix120@gmail.com

> LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Criminology as well as 4+ years of experience with the Army's customs and courtesies through ROTC and holds an active secret clearance. Recently earned a Certificate in Full Stack web Development from the University of California, Berkeley. Effective at combining resilience with problem solving to create dynamic web applications.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, React, JSX, JSON, ES6

Applications: Web API, Rest API, Postman, AJAX, Node.js, jQuery, Express.js, Passport, bcrypt, React hooks, Bootstrap, Sequelize ORM, MySQL, Mongoose ORM, Mongodb, cloudinary Materialize, Heroku, Git, GitHub

PROJECTS

Travel Pins | GitHub: https://github.com/anusontarangkul/travel-pins | Deployed Project: https://travel-pins.herokuapp.com

- Co-developed a travel social media application
- Formulated the backend server, database, Rest API, and worked on the frontend javascript
- Contributed over 80% of the additions made to the repository
- Applied tools / languages used: JavaScript, SQL, CSS, HTML, JSX, JSON, ES6, Node.is, bcryptis, cloudinary. Express, Express-session, if-env, mysql2, Passport, Passport-local, Sequelize, mapbox-gl, re-carousel, React, React-dom, React-icons, React-router-dom, React-scripts, React-spring, React-swipeable, React-transition-group, web-vitals

Employment Buddy|GitHub: https://github.com/hondahelix/employment-buddy|Deployed Project: https://employmentbuddy.herokuapp.com

- Co-developed an application to assist users in staying organized during the job hunting process
- Primarily managed frontend JavaScript as well as API calls
- Tools / languages used: Javascript, CSS, HTML, SQL, bcrypt.js, dragula.js, Express, jQuery, MySQL, Passport, Sequelize, Bulma, Undraw, Font Awesome

Google Book Search | GitHub: https://github.com/hondahelix/google-book-search | Deployed Project: https://salty-chamber-90587.herokuapp.com

- Co-developed MERN application that utilizes the Google Books API search for and adds a book to a reading list
- Designed the front-end code to display relevant information to the user and the routes to save the data
- Applied tools / languages used: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, JSX, React, Axios, Express, Mongoose, Mongodb, React-Router-Dom

EXPERIENCE

Network Officer/Division Signal Company

2020 - Present Los Alamitos, CA

Newly ranked second lieutenant, responsible for maintaining the Army's voice, data, and information systems as well as the development and readiness of a platoon

Cadet Troop Leader Training/510th Clearance Company, 20th Engineering Battalion

2019 - 2019Fort Hood, TX

Acted as platoon leader for a 32-soldier route clearance platoon with the mission to rapidly deploy to a combat theater and execute explosive hazard detection. Responsible for planning, resourcing, coordinating, fitness, professional development, discipline, and combat readiness of the platoon for three weeks.

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley - Full-Stack Web Development Certificate

September 2020 - December 2020

University of California, Irvine - Bachelor of Arts in Criminology, Law, and Society

September 2016 - September 2020